Dongho Kang

Sumatrastrasse 11, Zurich 8092, Switzerland kangd@ethz.ch • +41 78 677 90 49 • https://donghok.me/

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research aims to create a legged robot that can perform natural, animal-like motion. Thus, my research interests are broad ranging to legged locomotion control, computational model of character animation and design optimization for robotics applications.

EDUCATION

ETH Zürich, Zurich, Switzerland

■ Doctoral Student in Computer Science

Apr 2020 - Present

• Advisor: Prof. Dr. Stelian Coros

M.Sc. ETH in Mechanical Engineering

Sep 2016 – Aug 2019

• Advisor: Prof. Dr. Marco Hutter

· Graduated with distiction

Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

■ B.Sc. in Mechanical Engineering and B.Sc. in Computer Science

Mar 2009 – Aug 2016

• Advisor: Prof. Dr. Dongjun Lee

· Graduated with honor (Cum Laude)

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Computational Robotics Lab, ETH Zürich

Scientific Assistant

Dec 2019 – Present

• Supervisors: Prof. Dr. Stelian Coros

Aim to build bio-inspired quadrupedal robots that perform more natural and animal-like motion.

Robotic Systems Lab, ETH Zürich

Master's Student

Sep 2017 – Nov 2019

Supervisors: David Höller, Dr. Jemin Hwangbo and Prof. Dr. Marco Hutter

• Conducted the research on learning-based collision avoidance method for a legged robot ANYmal.

• Participated in the development of RaiSim: a physics engine for robotics and AI research.

Interactive & Networked Robotics Lab, Seoul National University

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Sep 2014 – Jan 2016

• Supervisors: Prof. Dr. Dongjun Lee

· Participated in the research on state estimation and control strategy for multi-robot cooperative systems

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS & ACTIVITIES

NVIDIA, Zurich, Switzerland

Deep Learning Intern

Jun 2018 – Dec 2018

· Projects: Super-Resolution and Anti-aliasing methods based on deep learning.

LeisureQ Inc., Seoul, South Korea

Web Developer Intern

Jan 2016 – Sep 2016

• Projects: Backend web application for E-commerce website Gajago: http://www.thegajago.com

CNP Technology Inc., Seoul, South Korea

Hardware and CAD Engineer

Jan 2016 – Sep 2016

PUBLICATIONS

THESIS

[1] <u>Dongho Kang</u>, "End-to-End Collision Avoidance from Depth Input with Memory-based Deep RL," <u>MSc thesis</u>, the Department of Mechanical and Process Engineering, ETH Zürich, Aug 2019.

CONFERENCES

- [1] Dongho Kang, Simon Zimmermann, and Stelian Coros, "Animal Gaits on Quadrupedal Robots using Motion Matching and Model-Based Control," in *International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)*, Mar 2021 (accepted.)
- [2] Flavio De Vincenti, <u>Dongho Kang</u>, and Stelian Coros, "Control-Aware Design Optimization for Bio-Inspired Quadruped Robots," in *International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)*, Mar 2021 (accepted.)

[3] Changu Kim, Hyunsoo Yang, <u>Dongho Kang</u> and Dongjun Lee, "2-D Cooperative Localization with Omni-Directional Mobile Robots," in *International Conference on Ubiquitous Robots and Ambient Intelligence*, Goyang, South Korea, Oct 2015.

INVITED TALK

Robot Intelligence Lab, Korea University, Seoul, South Korea

Apr 2021

NAVER LABS Corp., Seoul, South Korea

Dec 2019

• Max Planck ETH Center for Learning Systems Symposium, Tübingen, Germany

Feb 2019

AWARDS & SCHOLARSHIPS

■ Birkigt Scholarship, ETH Zürich

Feb 2018

Stipendiary scholarship for international master student.

Aug 2014

Eminence Scholarship, Seoul National University
 Full-tuition scholarship for one academic semester for outstanding academic performance.

Aug 2014

Morit based Scholarchip Secul National University

Feb 2014

Merit-based Scholarship, Seoul National University
 Half-tuition scholarship for one academic semester for outstanding academic performance.

Feb 2014

Development Fund Scholarship, Seoul National University

Feb 2010

Full-tuition scholarship for one academic year for outstanding academic performance.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

ETH Zürich, Zurich, Switzerland

Teaching Assistant, Computational Models of Motion

Mentor, SNU Samsung Convergence Software Course Program

Feb 2021 – Jun 2021 Sep 2020 – Dec 2020

■ Teaching Assistant, Visual Computing

Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

Jan 2015 – Dec 2015

■ Teaching Assistant, MAE 446.204A: Dynamics

Jan 2014 – Dec 2014

■ Teaching Assistant, PA 034.013: Basic Physics 2

Sep 2011 – Dec 2011

LANGUAGES

Korean: Native language.

English: Fluent (speaking, reading, writing).

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming and Software

C/C++, C#, Python, Matlab/Octave, Unix/Linux, Tensorflow, Pytorch, ROS, Open Dynamics Engine, Unity

Experience with Robots

Laikago, Aliengo, A1, ANYmal, GhostRobotics Vision60

REFERENCES

■ Prof. Dr. Stelian Coros

Assistant Professor in the Department of Computer Science

ETH Zürich

Stampfenbachstrasse 48 (Sumatrastrasse 11), 8092, Zurich, Switzerland

scoros@inf.ethz.ch • +41 44 632 02 15

■ Prof. Dr. Marco Hutter

Assistant Professor in the Department of Mechanical and Process Engineering

ETH Zürich

Leonhardstrasse 21, 8092 Zurich, Switzerland

mahutter@ethz.ch • +41 44 632 74 17

■ Prof. Dr. Jemin Hwangbo

Assistant Professor in the Department of Mechanical Engineering

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology

jhwangbo@kaist.ac.kr

■ Prof. Dr. Dongjun Lee

Professor in the Department of Mechanical Engineering

Seoul National University

1 Gwanak-Ro, Gwanak-Gu, Seoul, 08826, South Korea

djlee@snu.ac.kr • +82 2 880 1724